#### **Contact Information**

#### **Email**

fede.lopez89@gmail.com

## **Address**

Lomas de Zamora, Buenos Aires, Argentine.

## **Phone**

(+54911) 5501-9617

## Date of birth

03-11-1989

# Nationality

Argentinian

#### Link

https://ar.linkedin.co m/publicprofile/in/federicogabriel-lópezb8754254?

## Skills

COBOL

CICS

JCL

VSAM

DB2

CONTROL-M

HTML5

CSS3

**JAVASCRIPT** 

**BOOTSTRAP** 

SASS/LESS

REACT

**NODEJS** 

**EXPRESS** 

MONGO DB

## Languages

## Spanish

Native

## **English**

Advanced

# Federico Gabriel López

## Fullstack Developer | COBOL Mainframe Developer

I'm a Fullstack Web Developer and Mainframe Cobol Developer with more than ten years of experience in technology providing my services within the banking area.

I am a passionate individual always wanting to learn more about software engineering and computer science. I consider myself a quick learner always setting out challenges to learn different programming concepts and to find a more efficient way of solving problems.

## Experience

Buenos Aires, Argentina August 2020 - Present

Buenos Aires, Argentina 2018 - Present

Buenos Aires, Argentina February 2015 - Present

Buenos Aires, Argentina February 2014 - January 2015

Buenos Aires, Argentina October 2012 - February 2014

Buenos Aires, Argentina March 2010 - September 2012

# ■ Front-End Web Developer

## ICBC

I started taking development on frontend tasks in particular on ReactJs for an internal app in the bank for the area of compliance.

# Fullstack Web Developer

#### Freelance

Development of applications and websites applying the latest technologies on the market. I give complete solutions, front-end and backend

Some of the tools and languages used: HTML5, CSS, GitHub, React Js, Node Js, Mongodb, among others.

# ■ Sr Mainframe COBOL Developer

## CBC

Area: Anti-Money Laundering
Impact analysis. Effort's estimation and budget
developments. COBOL programming. BATCH & Online
(CICS/ALTAMIRA) using VSAM / QSAM files, MQ and
DB2. Unit, integral and user tests.

## Functional Analyst COBOL

## ISBAN

Area: Risk managment (systems in recovery)
Review and acceptance of requirements.
Preparation of technical designs for delivery to
a Soft Factory. Acceptance and approval of
developments made by them. Attention to
productive incidents.

# Sr Mainframe COBOL Developer BBVA

Area: Market and Liabilities.
Functional analysis. Impact analysis.
Development of COBOL components in TSO/HOST.

## Cobol Developer

## Accenture

Project: IBERDROLA from Spain.

Development of COBOL components Batch and Cics.

Use of DB2, MQ, JCLs. Use of CMii 3.

## Education

BA, Argentina 2020 - 2021

BA, Argentina 2008 - 2015

BA, Argentina 2004 - 2006 FullStack NodeJs Education IT

Computer systems Engineering National University of Technology Incompleted. Third year reached.

Bachelor's degree in Business Administration Institute Euskal - Echea

# **Projects**

Portfolio-URL: https://federicoglopez.herokuapp.com/